Pitt Jazz Collection, 1971-2011 UA.90.8.26.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pitt Jazz Collection
1971-2011
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Davis, Nathan T. (Nathan Tate)
UA.90.8.26.1
48 Linear Feet
The Pitt Jazz Collection contains manuscript, photographic, and audio/video materials documenting the first 30 years of jazz activities at the University of Pittsburgh. The bulk of the collection relates to the University of Pittsburgh's Annual Jazz Seminar, but other topics include the Jazz Studies Department, the International Jazz Academy Hall of Fame, International Jazz Archives Journal, and Dr. Nathan Davis, founder and longtime director of the university's Jazz Studies Program.
History
The University of Pittsburgh's jazz program was founded in 1969 and is among one of the oldest collegiate jazz programs in the country. After the university's music department became only the nation's third college to establish a formal jazz curriculum, Dr. Nathan Davis, a professional saxophonist and music educator was brought in to lead the program's development and establish a jazz ensemble. Dr. Davis led and grew the jazz studies at Pitt for forty four years until his retirement in 2013 when world renowned jazz pianist and Pitt Alumna, Geri Allen, took over as director of the University of Pittsburgh's Jazz Studies Program.
The university's Jazz Ensemble was founded in the early days of Dr. Davis' tenure as director with less than a dozen musicians. Since that time, the group has grown in both number and stature. Within three years of its formation, the Pitt Jazz Ensemble had risen from performing locally to performing at the internationally known Montreux Jazz Festival in Montreux, Switzerland. The jazz ensemble has also toured the Southern United States, Barbados, Trinidad and Tobago, and Jamaica. They perform annually at a spring concert that has featured a number of notable jazz performers as featured artists.
Over the years, Pitt Jazz has perhaps become best known for its long running annual jazz seminar and concert. The event, now a staple of the Pittsburgh music scene, sprang from an impromptu event over forty years ago when Pittsburgh native and legendary jazz drummer Art Blakey and the Jazz Messengers were playing a date in Pittsburgh's Hill District. Dr. Davis, who had formerly toured with Blakely, approached the musician and asked if he could give a workshop to some of his jazz students. Despite the short notice, it was an overwhelming success. The success of Art Blakely's lecture prompted Dr. Davis to design and propose an annual university event that would bring multiple artists to the university each year. The plans eventually culminated in the University of Pittsburgh Jazz Seminar. The annual three day seminars include workshops given by professional jazz artists, where they are able to impart invaluable knowledge of their craft and the music industry to students, music educators, and the public, and a concluding 'all-star' concert to wrap up the weekend. The Pitt Jazz Seminar and Concert has had the has hosted a number of jazz legends including, Dizzy Gillespie, Miles Davis, Clark Terry, Sonny Rollins, Kenny Clarke and Grover Washington, Jr.. The success of the University of Pittsburgh Jazz Seminar inspired the creation of two additional jazz entities at university, International Academy of Jazz Hall of Fame and the International Jazz Archives Journal.
In 1977, Pitt Jazz established the International Academy of Jazz Hall of Fame to honor artists who have made extraordinary contributions to the musical genre. When the hall of fame was founded it was the first of its kind on any college campus. The hall of fame's inaugural inductees were five indisputable jazz legends: Louis Armstrong, Duke Ellington, Art Tatum, Charlie Parker, and Billie Holiday. Two new members were added to the hall of fame's ranks each year based on the votes of an international committee of jazz experts. The yearly inductions were often celebrated in conjunction with the annual University of Pittsburgh Jazz Seminar. In 1984 the International Academy of Jazz Hall of Fame unveiled a permanent display in the William Pitt Union. The display, which is open to the public, contains unique memorabilia and artifacts of hall of fame inductees such as an original painting by Miles Davis, a saxophone and trumpet accessories donated by Sonny Rollins and Clark Terry respectively, and a letter from Kenny Clarke to Charlie Parker.
Arising from a desire to parlay the successful discourse surrounding jazz during the seminar into more sustainable conversations, Dr. Nathan Davis founded the International Jazz Archives Journal in 1992. The yearly journal, edited by Davis, covered jazz education and scholarship, and analysis of the work acclaimed jazz artists, workshop transcripts from a prior jazz seminar, poetry, and music reviews.
Scope and Content Notes
The collection contains records of the first 30 years of Pitt Jazz from 1970-2001. The bulk of collection and most complete set of records relate to the annual Pittsburgh Jazz Seminar and Concert. Records pertaining to other elements of the university's jazz program such as the International Academy of Jazz Hall of Fame, International Jazz Archives Journal, jazz studies academic and ensemble records, and Dr. Nathan Davis can be also found within the collection but they are not as comprehensive in nature in terms of time period and thematic areas covered.
The manuscript portions of the collection contain a variety of materials including correspondence, organization and planning documents for a number of activities including the jazz seminar, the hall of fame, and journal. The collection also contains ephemera and promotional materials, journal drafts, and drafts of books authored by Dr. Davis.
The photographic and audio/video materials work in tandem with the manuscript materials described above by adding a richer level of documentation. The bulk of the collection's media is photographs and audio/video recordings of Pitt Jazz Seminar and Concert. The recordings include both audio and video recordings of individual seminar workshops and the seminar's culminating concert. Other audio/video media relates to jazz ensemble performances, student improvisation and arrangement assignments, and select recordings and compositions of Dr. Nathan Davis.
Arrangement
The Pitt Jazz Collection is arranged into the following seven series:
Series I. Pitt Jazz Seminar and Concert, 1971-1999
Series II. International Academy of Jazz Hall of Fame, 1977-1999
Series III. International Jazz Archives Journal, 1993-2006
Series IV. Jazz Studies, ca.1971-2000
Series V. Nathan Davis, ca. 1969-2000
Series VI. Photographic Material, ca. 1971-2000
Series VII. Audio/Video Material, 1973-1999
Acquisition Information
Gift of Nathan Davis on February 1, 2007.
Previous Citation
Pitt Jazz Collection, 1971-2001, UA.90.8.26.1, University of Pittsburgh Archives, Archives Service Center
Access Restrictions
The following materials have restricted access: Series I. Pitt Jazz Seminar and Concert: Subseries 1-6. To access this material researchers must agree to sign a confidentiality agreement provided by the Archives Service Center. All other portions of the collection have no restrictions.
Separated Material
In addition to the records relating to the creation of the International Academy of Jazz Hall of Fame, the collection also contains artifacts donated to the Hall of Fame by inductees. These artifacts include musical instruments, photographs, artwork and momentos. Further inquiries into the nature and scope of the donated material can be directed to staff of the Archives Service Center.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
All of the sound and video recordings require playback equipment available in the Archives Service Center. Please give ASC staff atleast 24 hours advanced notice if you wish to listen or watch material from the collection.
Music education; Jazz studies; Music; Jazz; University of Pittsburgh; Music -- Instruction and study; Music performance; Jazz ensemble with band; African American jazz musicians -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; University of Pittsburgh. Sonny Rollins International Jazz Archives; University of Pittsburgh. International Academy of Jazz Hall of Fame; University of Pittsburgh. Music Department; Davis, Nathan T. (Nathan Tate); University of Pittsburgh Jazz Seminar
- Pitt Jazz Seminar and Concert, 1971-2011; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains records related to the Pitt Jazz Seminar. Specifically the materials include, budget and planning documents, correspondence, participant contracts and biography information, promotional material, press, and a small number of seminar workshop transcripts. All materials in the Finance and Budget, Internal Correspondence, Outgoing Correspondence, Incoming Correspondence is restricted for access until further review. The Promotional and Press and Jazz Seminar Transcript subseries are arranged chronologically; the Participant Relations series is arranged alphabetically by artist last name.
  - Finance and Budget [Restricted], 1971-2008; 1.
    - Finance and Budget, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Finance and Budget, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Finance and Budget, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Finance and Budget, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Finance and Budget, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Finance and Budget, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Finance and Budget, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Finance and Budget, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Finance and Budget, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Finance and Budget, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Finance and Budget, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Finance and Budget, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Finance and Budget, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Finance and Budget, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Finance and Budget, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 183)
    - Finance and Budget, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Finance and Budget, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Finance and Budget, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Finance and Budget, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Finance and Budget, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Finance and Budget, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Finance and Budget, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Finance and Budget, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Finance and Budget, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Finance and Budget, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Finance and Budget, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Finance and Budget, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Finance and Budget, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Finance and Budget, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Finance and Budget, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 184)
    - Finance and Budget, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 185)
    - Finance and Budget, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 186)
    - Finance and Budget, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 187)
    - Finance and Budget, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 188)
    - Finance and Budget, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 189)
    - Finance and Budget, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 190)
  - Planning [Restricted], 1972-2008; 2.
    - Planning, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Planning, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Planning, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Planning, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Planning, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Planning, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Planning, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Planning, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Planning, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Planning, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Planning, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Planning, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Planning, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Planning, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Planning, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Planning, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Planning, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Planning, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Planning, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Planning, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Planning, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Planning, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Planning, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Planning, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Planning, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Planning, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Planning, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Planning, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - Planning, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Planning, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Planning (2), 2003 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Planning, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 194)
    - Planning (2), 2004 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Planning, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 195)
    - Planning, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 196)
    - Planning, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 197)
  - Internal Correspondence [Restricted], 1971-2001; 3.
    - Internal Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Internal Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Internal Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Internal Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Internal Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Internal Correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Internal Correspondence, 1991-2000 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Jazz Seminar Think Tank, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Outgoing Correspondence [Restricted], 1971-2001; 4.
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1976-1984 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1985-2000 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Jazz Seminar Think Tank, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Incoming Correspondence [Restricted], 1971-2001; 5.
    - Incoming Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 1985-2000 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Jazz Seminar Think Tank, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Promotional and Press, 1971-2011; 7.
    - Press Releases, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Press Releases, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Press Releases, 1990-2008 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Flyers, 1917-1978 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Flyers, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Flyers, 1990-2000 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Mailings, 1972-2010 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Newspaper Ads (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Posters, 1984-2016 (Map-case 12, Drawer 16)
    - Concert Tickets (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Concert Programs, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Concert Programs, 1990-2011 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Reception Invitations, 1983-2000 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Tenth Anniversary Calendar, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - News Clippings, 1971-1979 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Concert Programs, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - News Clippings, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - News Clippings, 1983-1990 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - News Clippings, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - News Clippings, 1998-2002 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Jazz Seminar Promotional Press Releases, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - University of Pittsburgh Musci Department, Concerts, 1994-1995 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Live Jazz at Pitt CD Planning, 1995-2001 (Box 52, Folder 48)
    - Live Jazz at Pitt CD Correspondence, 1995-2001 (Box 52, Folder 49)
    - Flyers, 2001 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - News Clippings, 1991-2001 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - The University of Pittsburgh -Contact!, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Univeristy of Pittsburgh Jazz Seminar All-Stars, 2000-2004 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - International Music Day, 2004-2006 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Port Authority Advertisements, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - 43rd-45th Annual Jazz Seminar and Concert Programs, 2013-2015 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Pitt Magazine, March 1987 (Box 29, Folder 104)
    - Pitt Jazz Week Proclamations, 1983 (Box 29, Folder 89)
    - Flyers and Posters, 2008-2009 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Flyers, 1981-2003 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Participant Relations, 1971-2006; 6.
    - Contracts [RESTRICTED], 1971-2006
      - Bill Abernathy [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Alex Acuna [RESTRICTED], 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Thomas Adams [RESTRICTED], 1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Ron Afiff [RESTRICTED], 2006 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Monty Alexander [RESTRICTED], 1981-1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Carl Allen [RESTRICTED], 2002 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Geri Allen [RESTRICTED], 1994-2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Alpha [RESTRICTED], 1983 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Komlo Amoaku [RESTRICTED], 1979-1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Pat Azzara [RESTRICTED], 2003 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Steven Backer [RESTRICTED], 1991 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Benny Bailey [RESTRICTED], 1981-1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Art Baker [RESTRICTED], 1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - David Baker [RESTRICTED], 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Kenny Barron [RESTRICTED], 1980-1999 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Dave Bjornson [RESTRICTED], 1999-2004 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Terrence Blanchard [RESTRICTED], 1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Oscar Brashear [RESTRICTED], 2000-2006 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Randy Brecker [RESTRICTED], 1985-2007 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Cecil Bridgewater [RESTRICTED], 2008 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Bob Brookmeyer [RESTRICTED], 1999 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Kenny Burrell [RESTRICTED], 1975 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - George Butler [RESTRICTED], 1973-1984 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Jaki Byard [RESTRICTED], 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Donald Byrd [RESTRICTED], 1971-2000 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - George Cables [RESTRICTED], 1984-1998 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Ron Carter [RESTRICTED], ca. 1971-1994 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Terri Lyne Carrington [RESTRICTED], 1993 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Phillip Catherine [RESTRICTED], 1992 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - David Chertok [RESTRICTED], 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Leon "Ndugu" Chancler [RESTRICTED], 2006 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - James Cleveland [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Billy Cobham [RESTRICTED], 2003 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - William Cole [RESTRICTED], 1976-1996 (Box 6, Folder 34)
      - George Coleman [RESTRICTED], 1986 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - Ray Coleman [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - Larry Coryell [RESTRICTED], 1976-2008 (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - Hank Crawford [RESTRICTED], 1991-2000 (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - Pierre Davis, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - Richard Davis [RESTRICTED], 1971-1979 (Box 6, Folder 40)
      - Alan Dawson [RESTRICTED], 1971-1991 (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - Ina Dittka [RESTRICTED], 1991 (Box 6, Folder 42)
      - Ray Drummond [RESTRICTED], 1987 (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - Dave Dubas [RESTRICTED], 2001 (Box 6, Folder 44)
      - Ted Dunbar [RESTRICTED], 1982-1997 (Box 6, Folder 45)
      - Rich Engler [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Box 6, Folder 46)
      - Peter Erskine [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Box 6, Folder 47)
      - Kevin Eubanks [RESTRICTED], 1992-1997 (Box 6, Folder 48)
      - Jon Faddis [RESTRICTED], 1986-1998 (Box 6, Folder 49)
      - Leonard Feather [RESTRICTED], 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 50)
      - Art Farmer [RESTRICTED], 1992 (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - Clare Fischer [RESTRICTED], 1993 (Box 6, Folder 52)
      - Charlie Fishman [RESTRICTED], 1989 (Box 6, Folder 53)
      - Tommy Flannigan [RESTRICTED], 1980-1985 (Box 6, Folder 54)
      - Boo Frazier [RESTRICTED], 1997 (Box 6, Folder 55)
      - Hans Fridulnd [Restricted], 1994 (Box 6, Folder 56)
      - Curtis Fuller [RESTRICTED], 1993-2000 (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - Bobbie Fulton [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 6, Folder 58)
      - Eric Gale (Gale Pyramid Music Inc.) [RESTRICTED], 1983-1991 (Box 6, Folder 59)
      - Dizzy Gillespie [RESTRICTED], 1973 (Box 6, Folder 60)
      - Elias Gistelinck [RESTRICTED], 1978-1984 (Box 6, Folder 61)
      - Ira Gitler [RESTRICTED], 1978-1987 (Box 6, Folder 62)
      - Eddie Gomez [RESTRICTED], 1981-1985 (Box 6, Folder 63)
      - Benny Golson [RESTRICTED], 1993-2007 (Box 6, Folder 64)
      - Dexter Gordon [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 6, Folder 65)
      - Johnny Griffin [RESTRICTED], 1983-1996 (Box 6, Folder 66)
      - Gospel Chords [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 67)
      - Jim Hall [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 68)
      - Marv Halliday [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 69)
      - Slide Hampton [RESTRICTED], 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 70)
      - Roland Hana [RESTRICTED], 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 71)
      - Winard Harper [RESTRICTED], 1997-2006 (Box 6, Folder 72)
      - Joe Harris [RESTRICTED], 1972 (Box 6, Folder 73)
      - Donald Harrison [Restricted], 2006 (Box 6, Folder 74)
      - Antonio Hart [RESTRICTED], 2008 (Box 6, Folder 75)
      - Lou Hayes [RESTRICTED], 1975 (Box 6, Folder 76)
      - Jimmy Heath [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Box 6, Folder 77)
      - Percy Heath [RESTRICTED], 1993 (Box 6, Folder 78)
      - Eddie Henderson [RESTRICTED], 1998 (Box 6, Folder 79)
      - Joe Henderson [RESTRICTED], 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 80)
      - Mike Hennessey [RESTRICTED], 1978-1998 (Box 6, Folder 81)
      - Neils Hennings [RESTRICTED], 1991 (Box 6, Folder 82)
      - Nat Hentoff [RESTRICTED], 1998 (Box 6, Folder 83)
      - Terumasa Hino [RESTRICTED], 1978-1997 (Box 6, Folder 84)
      - Freddie Hubbard [RESTRICTED], 1984-2000 (Box 6, Folder 85)
      - Milt Jackson [RESTRICTED], 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 86)
      - Illinois Jacquet [RESTRICTED], 1991 (Box 6, Folder 87)
      - Suzan Jenkins [RESTRICTED], 2001 (Box 6, Folder 88)
      - Willard Jenkins [RESTRICTED], 1999 (Box 6, Folder 89)
      - Niranjan Jhaveri [RESTRICTED], 1990 (Box 6, Folder 90)
      - Elvin Jones [RESTRICTED], 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 91)
      - Hank Jones [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 92)
      - Thad Jones [RESTRICTED], 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 93)
      - Burt Korall [RESTRICTED], 1980 (Box 6, Folder 94)
      - Lee Konitz [RESTRICTED], 1980 (Box 6, Folder 95)
      - Abraham Laboriel [RESTRICTED], 1976-2007 (Box 6, Folder 96)
      - David Laing [RESTRICTED], 1998 (Box 6, Folder 97)
      - John Lewis [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Box 6, Folder 98)
      - Kirk Lightsey [RESTRICTED], 2001 (Box 6, Folder 99)
      - Mike Longo [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 6, Folder 100)
      - Joe Lovano [RESTRICTED], 2001-2004 (Box 6, Folder 101)
      - Russell Malone [RESTRICTED], 1999 (Box 6, Folder 102)
      - Bob Magnusson [RESTRICTED], 2002 (Box 6, Folder 103)
      - Herbie Mann [RESTRICTED], 1986-1998 (Box 6, Folder 104)
      - Ellis Marsalis [RESTRICTED], 1990 (Box 6, Folder 105)
      - Pat Martino [RESTRICTED], 2003 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      - Bennie Maupit [RESTRICTED], 2008 (Box 6, Folder 107)
      - Mike McFadin [RESTRICTED], 2006 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      - Tom McIntosh [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      - Jackie McLean [RESTRICTED], 1997 (Box 6, Folder 110)
      - Charles McPherson [RESTRICTED], 2001 (Box 6, Folder 111)
      - Mulgrew Miller [RESTRICTED], 1996 (Box 6, Folder 112)
      - T.S. Monk [RESTRICTED], 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 113)
      - Marcio Montarroyos [RESTRICTED], 1990 (Box 6, Folder 114)
      - James Moody [RESTRICTED], 1972-1999 (Box 6, Folder 115)
      - Dan Morgenstern [RESTRICTED], 1971-2006 (Box 6, Folder 116)
      - Michael Mossman [RESTRICTED], 1987-2008 (Box 6, Folder 117)
      - George Mraz [RESTRICTED], 2004 (Box 6, Folder 118)
      - Idris Muhammad [RESTRICTED], 1979-1998 (Box 6, Folder 119)
      - Joe Newman [RESTRICTED], 1974 (Box 6, Folder 120)
      - J.H. Kwabena Njetia [RESTRICTED], 1983 (Box 6, Folder 121)
      - Jimmy Owens [RESTRICTED], 1979-2006 (Box 6, Folder 122)
      - John Patitucci [RESTRICTED], 1997-2000 (Box 6, Folder 123)
      - Dave Pike [RESTRICTED], 2006 (Box 6, Folder 124)
      - Terry Pollard [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 125)
      - William Quinn [RESTRICTED], 1973 (Box 6, Folder 126)
      - Jaree Reed [RESTRICTED], 1983 (Box 6, Folder 127)
      - Claus Reichstaller [RESTRICTED], 2007 (Box 6, Folder 128)
      - Eric Reed [RESTRICTED], 2002 (Box 6, Folder 129)
      - Rufus L. Reid [RESTRICTED], 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 130)
      - Larry Ridley [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Box 6, Folder 131)
      - Phil Rizzo [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 6, Folder 132)